Lloyd: So now that you've completed
session two of unit one, it's
time to complete the relevant
section of the assessment booklet.
So if you open your assessment
booklet and scroll down to section
two: Job Functions in Coding.
And as you can see at the top, the
learning objectives that you need to
meet in the questions is at the top,
and also importantly, the location in
the course materials if you need to
refer back to the materials to support
you or to assist you with your answers.
There is also some additional information
here asking you to do some research,
to find examples of the following,
which is: coding professional rules;
coding careers and progression routes;
coding team roles; team-working
and project management skills.
Fully understanding all of these will help
you to complete the questions or several
of the questions within this section.
So for question one, it's asking
you in the box below from your
research, list the key job functions
and the key skills that will be
required for a coding professional.
So what are the job functions that a
coding professional will carry out?
And what key skills do they need?
And for key skills, think about the
soft skills, this isn't just about
being able to program or understanding
coding languages, this is about
the skills that they will need.
A lot of it relates to soft skills
when they're working in teams and
that, so think about that when
you're formulating your response.
For question two, it's asking you
to list the different roles that
you would find in coding team.
Most coders don't work in isolation,
they are responsible for a specific
task or a specific role within a team.
So what are the different roles that
you would find within a coding team?
And again, it's a list question, so
you can just list your responses.
For question three, this is an explain
question, so try and provide good detail
in your response and, you know, explain
in your own words why team-working and
project management skills are important.
So think about why teamworking
skills is important and what
will [it] help you achieve?
What are the benefits of being able to
work effectively within a team and also
having good project management skills?
For question four, in the box below
from your research, list the different
career and career progression routes.
So think about the different
careers that are available
to people who work in coding.
So there's a variety of different things.
So list -- again, it's a list
question -- so you can just list your
answer and the career progression.
So, think about where they can go from,
if you start in a specific type of career,
what are the potential opportunities
available to that person within that?
Where can they go from that?
Again, use your research and refer to the
course materials for guidance with that.
Once you've completed question four
you can then carry out a spelling
and grammar check, proofread through
your answers to ensure that you're
happy with them and then save your
assessment and carry on to session three.